The Canterville Ghost is a tv movie, fantasy, drama
film directed by Sydney Macartney.
When a teenaged girl moves to England, with her brothers and parents
into the ancient Canterville Hall, she's not at all happy.
Especially as there's a ghost and a mysterious
re-appearing bloodstain on the hearth.
She campaigns to go back home, and her dad, believing the ghost's
pranks are Ginny's, is ready to send her back.
But then Ginny actually meets the elusive 17th-century Sir Simon de Canterville (not to mention the cute
teenaged duke next door), and she sets her hand to the task of freeing Sir Simon from his curse.
Sir Simon de Canterville, played by Patrick Stewart.
Virginia 'Ginny' Otis, played by Neve Campbell.
Mrs. Umney, played by Joan Sims.
Mr. Umney, played by Donald Sinden.
Lucille Otis, played by Cherie Lunghi.
George, Lord Canterville, played by Leslie Phillips.
The Canterville Ghost is a 1996 family film directed by Sydney Macartney.
The mystery, romance, and adventure stars Patrick Stewart and Neve Campbell; it is based on an 1887 Oscar Wilde
short story of the same title which was serialized in the magazine The Court and Society Review.
This story has been adapted to film and made-for-TV movies several
times since the original film of the same name.
Filming was done at Knebworth House in Hertfordshire.
The film explores themes of england, prank, curse, ghost.
The tone is emotional.